ABHISHEK S DAWANGE

abhishek.dawange@gmail.com • 7768024507 • Pune, MH, IND • https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-dawange-62b3b7170/

Summary

Dynamic and Seasoned Software developer with experience of 3 years in designing and building applications. Quick Learner, Strong Troubleshooting Skills. Good communication and interpersonal skills.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks: C#, .Net Framework/Core, Angular, Java, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Node Js.

Database: MySQL, Oracle SQL Developer, MongoDb Atlas.

Webservices: Rest, SOAP

Repository: GitHub, Tortoise SVN **Others**: Swagger, SoapUl, Postman

Industry Experience

Associate (Full Stack Developer)

Nov 2020 - Oct 2023

Cognizant, Pune, MH, IND (Nov 2020 - Oct 2023)

Project: Massachusetts Property Insurance and Underwriting Association & RIJRA

- Resolved bugs occurred on Production Environment.
- Improved performance of some functionalities by updating logic and changing values of the attributes in Registries.
- Increased code quality by refactoring and adding adequate exception handling.
- Made changes to existing logic in order to add new feature to existing functionalities.
- Built REST APIs to cater the frontend part of the project.
- Unit testing for Repositories, Services and Controllers that improved code coverage from 71% to 83%.
- Made changes in the UI part of the application in order to improve responsiveness towards small devices like tabs and mobile phones.
- Design and Development of UI components.
- Resolved malfunctions with system and programs through troubleshooting.

Personal Projects

Movies Application

https://abhishekd.netlify.app/

- Technologies Used: React, JavaScript, HTML, Tailwind CSS.
- Designed and developed web application by fetching JSON data from TMDB API
- Functionalities added: Show movies, add movies to watchlist, delete movies from watchlist, search movies by Genre and Movie Name.
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Abhisd/Movies-App

Weather Forecast Web Application

- Technologies Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Designed and developed a single page application which gets data from api.weatherapi.com
- Functionalities added: Displaying the weather forecast for the city searched.
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Abhisd/WeatherApp

Personal Portfolio

https://abhisd.github.io/Portfolio-Design/

- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS.
- Designed and developed static web page displaying Professional details.
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Abhisd/Portfolio-Design

Education

Scaler Academy

DSA and Full Stack Development

June 2022 - Pursuing

Sinhgad Institute of Technology and Science, Pune – University of Pune

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science. Aug 2016 – Oct 2020

Accomplishments

Solved 300+ DSA problems on LeetCode: https://leetcode.com/AbhishekDawange/